jancisrobinson.com 2019-12-02

# Privacy and cookie policy | JancisRobinson.com

**PRIVACY AND COOKIE POLICY**

JancisRobinson.com Limited **(“JancisRobinson.com” / “we” / “our” / “us”)** takes your privacy very seriously and understands the importance of protecting your privacy and confidentiality.

If you wish to contact us regarding this Privacy and Cookie Policy, you can contact us:

  * by emailing [editorial@jancisrobinson.com](mailto:editorial@jancisrobinson.com);
  * by notifying us at our postal address of JancisRobinson.com Limited, 64 New Cavendish Street, London, W1G 8TB, United Kingdom; or
  * by contacting us using the Site’s Contact Us page found [here](https://www.jancisrobinson.com/contact).

Jancisrobinson.com Ltd (“ **us** ” or “ **we** ”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This Privacy and Cookie Policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, as a result of your visiting our website at [www.jancisrobinson.com](http://www.jancisrobinson.com/) (the “ **Site** ”) will be processed by us. It also provides you with information regarding our use of cookies.

Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it, and regarding cookies. **By using the Site you are accepting and consenting to the practices set out in this Privacy and Cookie Policy and also agreeing to abide by our Terms of Use.**

If you have not already read our Terms of Use, please do so [here](https://www.jancisrobinson.com/website-terms-of-use).

We are the data controller of the personal data we collect through the Site. We are a company registered in England and Wales under company number 04656187 and our registered office address is at 64 New Cavendish Street, London, W1G 8TB. We are VAT registered under number 821 1054 82.

**INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU**

We may collect and process the following data about you:

**Data you give us.** You may give us data about you:

  * when you use the Site;
  * when you contact us or send us an enquiry using the Contact Us form on the Site;
  * when you create an event on the calendar pages of the Site;
  * when you report a problem or issue with the Site;
  * when you register to become a Member in accordance with our Membership Terms;
  * when you input details on the forum pages of the Site; and
  * when you provide us with a testimonial about our products and/or services.

**Data we collect about you.** When you visit the Site we will automatically collect the following data about you:

  * details of your usage of the Site (including [the date,] [time,] [location or] [duration] of the usage).
  * certain technical information, for example, the type of device (and its unique device identifier) you use to access the Site, the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your device to the Internet, your login information (if you are a Member), browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system, mobile network information and platform.
  * information about your visit to the Site including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), clickstream to, through and from the Site (including date and time), pages you viewed, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page.

**CREDIT AND DEBIT CARD DETAILS**

Please note that we do not collect or process your credit or debit card details. However if you make payments through the Site these details are collected and processed by our payment processing service provider Stripe Payments Europe, Ltd (“ **Stripe** ”). The collection and processing by Stripe of your credit or debit card details and other personal data are governed by their terms and conditions: see <https://stripe.com/gb/privacy> for more information. Stripe may from time to time provide us with information regarding the credits and debits made to your card in order to enable us to reconcile our accounts.

**IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES**

We may collect information about your computer, including, where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and statistical analysis. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using cookies. A cookie is a small file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. They help us to improve the Site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. We use the following cookies:

**Strictly necessary cookies**. These are cookies that are required for the operation of the Site. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of the Site, use a shopping cart or make use of e-billing services.

**Analytical/performance cookies**. These allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around the Site when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way the Site works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.

**Functionality cookies**. These are used to recognise you when you return to the Site. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).

**Targeting cookies**. These cookies record your visit to the Site, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make the Site more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

**THE COOKIES THE SITE USES**

You can find more information about the individual cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them in the table below:

**Cookie name** | **Purpose**  
---|---  
session | This cookie is essential for the Site to operate. It allows us to remember your details during your current visit to the Site.  
cookie-agreed | This cookie allows us to know that you agreed to let us use cookies on the Site.  
_forum-session | This cookie allows us to remember your details during your current visit to the forum section of the Site.  
_t | This cookie allows the Site to share your login data with the forum, allowing you access to that part of the Site.  
Google Analytics | This are an analytical / performance cookies. The Site uses Google Analytics to help analyse how users use the Site, collecting standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information in an **anonymised** form from which no user is identifiable. This information is transmitted to Google and processed to compile statistical reports on activity on the Site. These reports allow us to optimise our user experience. Google provide a browser add-on for users who wish to prevent their data from being used by Google Analytics. [Click here](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html) for an overview of privacy at Google, and [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) if you wish to opt out from the operation of Google Analytics.  
  
If you have signed up to marketing emails from us, please note that MailChimp (our marketing automation platform) also uses cookies in our newsletters. Please see MailChimp’s Privacy Policy at <https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/> for more information.

If you are purchasing membership using the Site, please note that Stripe also uses cookies during the payment process. Please see Stripe’s cookie policy at <https://stripe.com/cookies-policy/legal> for more information.

By using the Site you accept our use of these cookies.

Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

**BLOCKING COOKIES**

You may block cookies by activating settings on your browser which allow you to refuse the setting of some or all cookies. If you choose to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or some parts of the Site.

Most cookies we use are known as session cookies. These cookies will expire whenever you close your browser or shut down your computer. Other cookies used for specific purpose will expire when that purpose is no longer required.

You can find out more about blocking cookies in specific browsers at [http://aboutcookies.org](http://aboutcookies.org/).

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

All information you provide to us or that we collect from you is stored on our secure servers within the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”) or on the servers of our respective hosting service providers, which we may change from time to time.

However, the personal data that we collect from you regarding your membership payment and your subscription to marketing emails will be transferred to, processed and stored at destinations outside the EEA, such as the United States.

There is no adequacy decision by the European Commission in respect of the United States, which means the United States is not deemed to provide an adequate level of protection to your personal data. However, to ensure that your personal data receives an adequate level of protection we have ensured that both MailChimp and Stripe are certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield to ensure that your personal data is treated by those third parties in a way that is consistent with EU and UK laws on data protection.

Any payment transactions will be encrypted using SSL technology.

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will use our best endeavours to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Site and any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use suitable procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the Site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.

**PURPOSE AND LEGAL BASIS FOR PROCESSING YOUR DATA**

We have set out below a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data on more than one legal basis depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal basis we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one basis has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose of processing** | **Type of personal data** | **Legal basis for processing**  
---|---|---  
To ensure that the content on the Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and your device | Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Site or otherwise by contacting us using the Contact Us form provided on the Site, and details of your visits to the Site including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, and the date, time and duration of your usage of the Site | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our services, to keep the Site updated and relevant, to develop our business, to inform our marketing strategy, for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise); and  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
For our internal operations, including data analytics, testing, research, statistical purposes and troubleshooting | Details of your usage (including the date, time, location and duration of your usage) and technical information as mentioned above | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep the Site updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To deal with any enquiries, correspondence, concerns or complaints you have raised via the Site | Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Site or otherwise by contacting us using the Contact Us form provided on the Site and copies of your correspondence with us.  
This information may include your name, address, date of birth, email address and any other information you provide to us when contacting us | (a) Performance of a contract with you  
(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to address our customers’ concerns and queries)  
To process your request to subscribe as a member to the Site | Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Site or otherwise by contacting us using the Contact Us form provided on the Site and copies of your correspondence with us.  
This information may include your name, address, date of birth, email address and any other information you provide to us when contacting us | Performance of a contract  
To enable us to display your uploaded wine-related event to the calendar pages on the Site | Your name, email address, details of the event and any other information you may provide whilst completing the event details form | Legitimate interest – to allow us to maintain the calendar on the Site  
To enable us to upload your posts and comments to the members’ forum on the Site | Your name and any other information you may provide as part of your post to the forum | Legitimate interest – to allow us to maintain the forum on the Site  
To provide you with information regarding our products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes | Information that you provide by filling in forms on the Site or otherwise by contacting us using the Contact Us form provided on the Site and copies of your correspondence with us.  
This information may include your name, address, date of birth, email address and any other information you provide to us when contacting us | Consent  
To use your reviews and comments as testimonials on the Site | Your name and any other information contained in your reviews and comments | Consent  
To process payments for membership subscriptions 

(Please see above in relation to credit and debit card details)

| Your name and bank, credit card or debit card details | Performance of a contract  
To process your entries to promotions, competitions and prize draws | Your title, name, email address, details of your entry to the promotion/competition/prize draw and any other information you may provide during the entrance procedure | Performance of a contract  
  
Where we have a legal basis to use your personal data without consent (as we have described above), this Privacy and Cookie Policy fulfils our duty to process personal data fairly and lawfully and in a manner that you would expect given the nature of our relationship with you, by giving you appropriate notice and explanation of the way in which your personal data will be used.

Where consent is required for our use of your personal data, by ticking the appropriate consent box or otherwise communicating your consent (for example, by email or by providing us with non-mandatory information), you consent to our use of that personal data as set out in this Privacy and Cookie Policy. For example, we will send you our weekly newsletter if we have your consent to do so.

You can always change your mind about our processing of your personal data. If you change your mind you can update your account settings within the Site, or contact us:

  * by emailing [editorial@jancisrobinson.com](mailto:editorial@jancisrobinson.com);
  * by notifying us at our postal address of JancisRobinson.com Limited, 64 New Cavendish Street, London, W1G 8TB, United Kingdom; or
  * by contacting us using the Site’s Contact Us page found [here](https://www.jancisrobinson.com/contact).

Or you can unsubscribe at any time by using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our marketing emails.

Except as provided below, we do not sell, trade or rent your personal information to third parties and will not share your personal information with third party advertisers.

**MARKETING**

As mentioned above, we would like to send you information by email about products, services and opportunities which may be of interest to you.

We will **not** provide your personal data to other businesses so they can use your personal data for marketing purposes.

We will only send you marketing messages if you would like us to. We may ask whether you would like us to send you marketing emails when you sign up to our weekly newsletter, when you sign up to the Site as a paid Member for the first time, or when you contact us via the Site. You will have the opportunity to clearly set out whether you wish to receive marketing emails from us by ticking the relevant box.

You can also manage your preferences by changing your account settings within the Site.

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

We may disclose your personal information to the following third parties:

  * those who help us run the Site, solely for the purposes of running the Site and performing the transactions concluded through the Site. These third parties include (but are not limited to) AWS (who host our servers) and Stripe (our payment processing service provider);
  * analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of the Site; 
  * any prospective buyer of or investor in our business in the event that we sell our business or assets or receive investment into our business;
  * any person to whom we sell or transfer all or substantially all of our assets, in which case personal data held by us about our customers will be one of the transferred assets;
  * any person to whom we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Website Use, Membership Terms or any other terms or agreements; and
  * government or other law enforcement agencies, in connection with the investigation of unlawful activities or for other legal reasons (this may include your location information).

**RETAINING PERSONAL DATA**

We will retain the personal data we receive or collect about you for the period reasonably required for us to use it in accordance with this Privacy and Cookie Policy or in accordance with our legal rights and obligations. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

Unless we inform you otherwise (or you request that we erase your personal data), we will retain your personal data on record for as long as you may continue to use the Site.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the following rights with regard to your personal data:

**Access.** You have the right to access data we hold about you.This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it;

**Rectification or erasure**. You have the right to request that we rectify or delete any personal data that we hold about you (unless we have the legal right to retain it). If you request that we erase any personal data that we require for your membership you may no longer be able to access the Purple Pages of the Site. This right does not extend to non-personal data. Please note that your rights to request erasure may be limited by applicable law.

**Restriction**.You also have the right to restrict us from processing your personal data if the data is inaccurate, the processing is unlawful or we no longer need to your personal data for the purposes for which we hold it.

**Data portability.** You have the right to obtain personal data we hold about you, in a structured, electronic format, and to transmit such data to another data controller if the legal basis for processing such personal data is your consent.

**Object /change of preferences**. You have a right to request that we stop processing your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party). Please note, if you submit a request for us to stop processing your personal data in a certain way and this type of processing is required in order to facilitate your membership, you will no longer be able to access the Purple Pages of the Site following your request for us to stop the relevant processing.

**Complaints.** If for any reason you are not happy with the way that we have handled your personal data, please contact us. If you are still not happy, you have the right to make a complaint to the Information Commissioner’s Office.

Please note that the rights mentioned above do not extend to **non-personal data**.

If you would like to exercise any of the rights mentioned above, please contact us:

  * by emailing [editorial@jancisrobinson.com](mailto:editorial@jancisrobinson.com);
  * by notifying us at our postal address of JancisRobinson.com Limited, 64 New Cavendish Street, London, W1G 8TB, United Kingdom; or
  * by contacting us using the Site’s Contact us page found [here](https://www.jancisrobinson.com/contact).

**Third Parties**

The Site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

Our website integrates Facebook and Twitter, which means that if you subscribe to the services provided by either Facebook, Inc. or Twitter, Inc. you can use those services as integrated into our website. Your use of those services (and any related use of your personal information) will be governed by the applicable terms and conditions of Facebook, Inc. and Twitter, Inc.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY AND COOKIE POLICY**

Any changes we may make to this Privacy and Cookie Policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. You should ensure that you review this Privacy and Cookie Policy from time to time. Continued use of the Site will signify that you agree to such changes.

**CONTACT US**

If you have any concerns about material which appears on the Site, or any questions, comments or requests regarding our Terms of Use, Membership Terms or this Privacy and Cookie Policy, please contact us:

  * by emailing [editorial@jancisrobinson.com](mailto:editorial@jancisrobinson.com);
  * by notifying us at our postal address of JancisRobinson.com Limited, 64 New Cavendish Street, London, W1G 8TB, United Kingdom; or
  * by contacting us using the Site’s Contact Us page found [here](https://www.jancisrobinson.com/contact).
